Slavick, Frederick Retirement Study Files /4016
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frederick Slavick Retirement Study Files
1963-1966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Slavick, Frederick
/4016
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Records relating to ILR faculty Frederick Slavick's study of retirement policies in the United States, in the late 1950s and early 1960s.
3084786
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 11, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 21, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Frederick Slavick (July 2, 1923 August 5, 1999) was a professor at Cornell University's School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A veteran of World War II, Slavick completed his BA and MA at University of Wisconsin-Madison (in 1946 and 1947, respectively). He completed his PhD in Economics at Princeton University in 1953, and joined the Cornell faculty in the same year. A Research Associate when he first arrived at Cornell, he was promoted to Assistant Professor in 1954, Associate Professor in 1960, and full Professor in 1966. He retired from the faculty of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1978.
Slavick worked at the Bureau of Labor and Management in the College of Commerce at the State University of Iowa for two years and published works relating to labor in Iowa, including "Voluntary Quits in Iowa" in Labor Law Journal 10:5 (May1959) and, with Jack F. Culley, "Employment Problems of Older Workers" as part of the Bureau's Informational Series (No. 1, 1959). He also published on retirement, insurance, and benefit plans for workers.
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor Frederick Slavick: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/17972
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of records relating to ILR faculty Frederick Slavick's study of retirement policies in the United States, in the late 1950s and early 1960s. Records include notes on interviews and research project design, questionnaires, and mimeographed reports based on the research by Edwin Schultz and Theron Fields.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3037: Frederick Slavick Papers
Slavick, Fred.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3084786
- Case studies: Harley Davidson, Fair Store, National Institute of Dry Cleaning, Central Light and Power Company, Trust National Bank of Minneapolis, Nash Engineering Corporation (Box 1)
  - Harley Davidson (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harley Davidson (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Binder
  - Harley Davidson - Draft of Case Study (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harley Davidson - Foreman Evaluations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Harley Davidson - Code for Transfer of Data from Unsort Cards to IBM Cards for Evaluated Employees (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harley Davidson - IBM List of Average Hourly Earnings, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Harley Davidson - Retiree Data Sheets, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harley Davidson - Information on Retirees (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Code for Deck 01
  - Harley Davidson (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fair Store - Foreman Evaluations (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fair Store (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fair Store - Retirees Lists (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fair Store (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Fair Store - Retirees Code Deck 01 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fair Store - Master Code for McBee Cards (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - National Institute of Drycleaning (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - National Institute of Drycleaning - Female Questionnaire 2, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - National Institute of Drycleaning, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Central Illinois Light and Power Co. - Code for Transfer of Data from Unsort Cards to IBM, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Central Illinois Light Co. - Retirees, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Central Illinois Light and Power Co. - Intensive Study, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Central Illinois Light Co. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - First National Bank of Minneapolis - Code for Transfer of Information (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - First National Bank of Minneapolis (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - First National Bank of Minneapolis - Corres., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - First National Bank, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Nash Engineering Company - Code for Unsort-IBM Transfer (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Nash Engineering Company, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Case studies: Nash Engineering Corporation, Koehring Company, Leich Electric Company, Corning Glass Company Conn Corporation, Carrier Corporation, Grede Foundry, Pohlman Foundry (Box 2)
  - Nash Engineering Company, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nash - Case Study Work Sheets (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nash Engineering - Master Copy, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nash (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Koehring Company, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Koehring Company (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Koehring - 1701 W. Wisc (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Koehring - Foreman Evaluations Deck 10 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Koehring - Code for Retirees (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Koehring Company - Master Code for Unsort Cards (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Koehring - Retirees Followup Letter on Mail Returns, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Koehring Company - Forms, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Leich Electric Company, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Leich Electric Company - J. Slauck (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Leich Electric Company (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Leich Electric Company - Retirees (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Corning Glass Co. - Code for Transfer of Information from McBee Cards to IBM Cards (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Corning Glass Co. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Corning Glass, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Corning Glass - Retiree Data, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Corning, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Conn Corporation (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Conn Corp., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - C. G. Conn Co. - Elkhart 2nd, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Conn Instrument Co. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Carrier Corp. - Code for Transfer of Data from Unsort and McBee Cards to IBM Cards for Evaluated Employees (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Carrier Corp. - Case Study, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Carrier Corp., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Carrier Corp. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Carrier Corp. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Carrier Corp., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Grede Foundry - Code for Transfer of Information from Unsort Cards to IBM Cards (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Grede - Retirees (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Grede Foundry (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Grede - Milwaukee (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Grede Foundry - Plans Completed, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pohlman Foundry, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Pohlman - Code for Unsort-IBM Transfer (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Pohlman Foundry (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Case studies: Grove Thread, Manning, Maxwell and Moore, Commonwealth Brass, Union Carbide Nuclear Company, Raytheon Company (Box 3)
  - Groves Thread (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Groves Thread - Retirees' Questionnaires (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Envelope
  - Groves Thread (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Groves Thread Co. - Interviews with Supervisors and Lists of Employees of Each (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Manning, Maxwell and Moore - Code for McBee-IBM (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Manning, Maxwell and Moore (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Manning, Maxwell and Moore, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Manning, Maxwell and Moore, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Elbe File and Binder Company (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth Brass, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth Brass - Transfer of Info from McBee Cards to IBM Cards, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    May 1966
  - Commonwealth Brass (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Union Carbide - National Laboratory (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ted's Union Carbide - Study, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Union Carbide Nuclear Co., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - ORNL Material (UCNC) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - ORNL - Top Management Interviews (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Union Carbide Nuclear Co. - Retirees (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - GDP Material - UCNC, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - UCNC - Retirees (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - UCNC - Policy Questionnaire, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Interviews with Supervisors UCNC - GDP (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Raytheon Company, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Raytheon (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous questionnaires and miscellaneous material (Box 4)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 1, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Long Forms - Sample 2, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 2, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 3, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Data Sheets, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Comparison of Independent Variables for 3rd Sample (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Comparison of Independent Variables for 2nd Sample (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 4, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 5, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 6, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 7, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 3rd Sample, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Print Out for Pittsburgh Paper, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Study of Retirement Policies folder 8, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Long Forms Returned - Sample 3, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Sample design and reports by Schultz and Theron (Box 5)
  - Sample Design, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sampling (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Black Copies of Master Code for Unsort Cards (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Policy Type 1-3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Deck 99 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Deck 98 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Deck 10 - Supervisor Evaluations (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Rohm and Haas - Case Study - Shultz (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Shultz - Preparation for Retirement, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Schultz - Social Agency Study (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Summary Version of Fields Early Ret. Study, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Company-Initiated Early Retirement as a Means of Work-Force Control copy 1, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Book
  - Company-Initiated Early Retirement as a Means of Work-Force Control copy 2, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)